Russia Miscellany Collection
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Russia Miscellany Collection 1759-1928
MSS38588
100 items
1 container plus 1 oversize
.2 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Miscellaneous documents relating to various topics. Includes manuscript of thanksgiving service for victory of Russian troops over King of Prussia at Frankfort am Main, Germay, 1759; letters in German relating to the Women's Association of Riga, Latvsa, 1846-1859; officer attendance records of the Nicolaevski Academy of the General Staff, St. Petersburg, Russia,1879-1881; and other papers.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
Organizations
Nicolaevski Academy of the General Staff (St. Petersburg, Russia); Russia. Armii︠a︡.; Women's Association of Riga.
Subjects
Seven Years' War, 1756-1763.; Women--Latvia--Societies and clubs.
Places
Prussia (Kingdom)--History.; Russia--History--1613-1917.
Provenance
The Russia Miscellany collection was acquired by the Library of Congress in the nineteenth and twentieth centuries.
Access and Restrictions
The collection of Russian Miscellany collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Scope and Content Note
The collection of Russia Miscellany spans the years 1759-1928 and includes a manuscript of thanksgiving service for victory of Russian troops over the King of Prussia at Frankfort am Main, Germany, 1759; letters in German relating to the Women's Association of Riga, Latvia,1846-1859; officer attendance records of the Nicolaevski Academy of the General Staff, St. Petersburg, Russia, 1879-1881; and other papers. Material is in Russian, German, and English.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is organized and described according to subject, name of person, or organization.
Container List
- Thanksgiving service for victory of Russian troops over the king of Prussia at Frankfurt am Main, Germany, 1759 (Box 1)
- Women’s Association of Riga, Latvia, cover letters for financial records sent to the grand duchess, 1846-1859 (Box 1)
- Nikolaevski Academy of the General Staff, St. Petersburg, Russia, monthly officer attendance (Box 1)
  - Monthly list, 1879-1881, (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - Sickness, 1881 (Box 1)
- Aeronautic District, 1st Detachment, payments, 1913 (Box 1)
- Marye, George Thomas, American ambassador to the Court of St. James, Order of St. Alexander Nevski, 1916 (Box 1)
- Council of the Subjugated Russians in Italy, 1919 (Box 1)
- Formation of shock revolutionary battalions, memorandum of General A. Lakonski, 1928 (Box 1)
- Oversize (Box OV 1)
  - Council of the Soviet Workers’ and Soldiers’ Deputies, law about land, 1917-1918 (Box OV 1)